Arseny Mamikonyan

City/Country:

Copenhagen, Denmark 2500 Phone number: +4525941123

E-mail:

arseny.mamikonyan@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/arseny-mamikonyan-668b83185/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a skilled and passionate Lead Mobile Engineer (iOS) with ~5 years of experience, I excel in creating, maintaining and improving native iOS applications using Swift. My expertise also extends to addressing cross-platform applications using Flutter. I thrive in problem-solving and am dedicated to maintaining good and structured documentation. I value close communication with team members to find the best solutions for the product. My passion for mobile development drives me to continuously learn and improve my skills and mentor and support others in their professional growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Mobile Engineer at Planday, Copenhagen — 11/2020 - Present

As a Lead Mobile Engineer, I successfully guided a team of 7 cross-platform engineers, including specialists in iOS and Android mobile platforms, Backend development, and QA. I played an instrumental role in researching, scoping, prioritizing, executing and releasing new product features. Each feature was aimed to enhance the user experience, reduced technical debt and introduced cutting-edge technologies for our developers. My leadership and technical expertise helped drive our team's and product's success. In addition to my technical responsibilities, I also mentored junior engineers and fostered a culture of collaboration and continuous learning within the team.

Key points of responsibilities:

- · Working with cross-platform, agile teams on scheduling application for iOS.
- Maintained high-quality, clean, maintainable and legible code with effective code reviews and covered all business logic with unit tests.
- Took an active part in managing technical depth by prioritizing work and features to reduce Objective-C code, separating features into separate modules and introducing and maintaining code style guidelines.
- Key person for maintaining CI/CD pipelines.
- Been involved in the recruiting process, code challenges reviews and technical interviews.
- Mentoring junior iOS developers.
- Introducing new colleagues to the product, codebase and getting them up to speed with team processes.
- Researching and developing features as a *project* lead.
- Been in close collaboration with multiple, cross-platform teams, designers and project managers.

- Facilitated and managed guild meetings/events for knowledge sharing, alignment on technologies/development approaches, and helping colleagues make decisions on complex business logic implementations.
- Participating in in-house hackathon events.
- Key technologies: Swift 5, Async/Await, SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, Objective-C, RxSwift, SwiftLint, Bitrise CI/CD, XCTests, RxTests, RxBlocking, Alamofire, Realm, Cuckoo.

iOS Developer at Emergn, Riga — 09/2018 - 11/2020

I have extensive experience working with agile teams on various projects, including a booking/traveling application and a certification/learning service. My domain knowledge includes user flow of flight/housing booking and I have been responsible for developing and releasing new features. I have also developed a native iOS application for 3D object interaction, messaging, and video calls from scratch. I have been a key person for CI/CD pipeline maintenance and introduced and supported CI/CD infrastructure that completely automated the team's deployment process and increased project development speed & quality. I have explored new technologies and introduced code coverage generation tools and static code analyzers to improve code quality and increase development speed. Additionally, I have worked with a team on micro-services implementation.

Key responsibilities:

- Worked with agile team on booking/traveling application. Main responsibilities: develop and release new features. Key technologies: Swift 4, AutoLayout, Apollo GraphQL client, RXSwift, MVVM pattern, SwiftLint, SQLite.
- I developed a native iOS application from scratch that enabled 3D object interaction, messaging, and video calls. Key technologies: TokBox, 3D Mapper, Swift 5, AutoLayout, SwiftLint. Key person for CI/CD pipeline maintenance using Fastlane, Gitlab CI/CD, Bash Scripting.
- Worked with a team on certification/learning services. Main responsibilities: development
 and support of application's networking layer, custom functionality for video player,
 participation in the code review process, helping colleagues on complex business logic
 implementation, communication with an outsourced team of backend developers, close
 communication with the client, and addressing new requirements. Key technologies: Swift
 5.2, AutoLayout, OfflineOData, Combine, FioriSDK for iOS.
- Developed cross platform applications such as: video interviewing, interactive questioner, virtual cash register and ticket wallet. Been a key person for cross-platform projects.
 Introduced multiple teams to Flutter framework and maintained high quality code standards.
 Key technologies: Flutter framework, Dart, Firebase, Amazon Web Services, GraphQL, BLoC and MVP patterns, Restful API.
- Introduced code coverage generation tools and static code analyzer to improve code quality and increase development speed. Key technologies: Dart analyzer, Slather, SonarQube, SwiftLint.
- Worked with a team on micro-services implementation. Key technologies: Node.js, TypeScript, Mmock, Jest, Kafka, MongoDB.

EDUCATION

September 2016 - July 2019

Riga Technical University | Riga

Name of qualification: Bachelor Degree of Engineering Science in Computer Control and Computer Science.

Main field(s) of study for the qualification: Study Programme "Computer Systems"

SKILLS

- Swift
- SwiftUI/Combine
- RxSwift
- Git
- · Objective-C
- Teamwork Communication
- Leadership
- Agile Scrum/Kanban

- Bash Scripting
- Flutter/Dart
- Fastlane
- Gitlab CI/CD
- Bitrise CI/CD
- NoSQL
- Typescript
- Node.js

LANGUAGES

English: Professional working proficiency

Latvian: Professional working proficiency

French: Basic proficiency

Russian: Native or bilingual proficiency

HOBBIES

- · Playing guitar and piano
- Photography
- · Active drone enthusiast
- Collecting vinyl records
- Solving Rubik's Cube puzzles
- Cooking cuisine of different cultures